I think Boris Johnson came out and said, like, fuck it, the UK businesses, they should prepare for a no deal by the end of the year.
The market actually doesn't care that much about a no deal.
I think there's some, like a general sentiment out there that Boris Johnson is just saying this shit.
But in response to that headline immediately, prices ended up down here within seconds.
Literally, just within seconds, I can actually show you on the TikTok.
On the TikTok.
But you can just imagine.
So it's not necessarily that there's a lot of selling going on.
They definitely would be sell orders, market order sells.
But most, most, you know, most prominently what's happening here is the bi-liquidity just disappeared, bro.
Nobody, or at least the algorithmic, you know, so the way the liquidity is provided on an automated basis in response to headlines, the bi-liquity is just removed.
This disappears, but nobody wants to go a bid.
that's a very mad move so this very second here is 1153 a.m. 309 seconds and 51 milliseconds
I think it's called and then 42 seconds so what was that? Yeah. Oh my day three seconds
seconds. All that move how many pips is that? 91. Wow 91 pips in three seconds. I tried
to buy it down here they wouldn't even fill me yeah i can see your level your levels right there as well
i had this level on from this low that was putting on wednesday oh that's a bit far back but
the low was putting on when when is wednesday there you go so that's 14th of october
had a level on and price just came retested it but um yeah so you know it's like that scenario
where price jumps 10% it looks as if it's a huge well it is a huge
move but not necessarily because of strong buying in this instance it's sold off 91 pips not necessarily
because of strong selling but more to do with how illiquid this move uh how illiquid the buy side was
yeah once the cell volume dried off very very quickly any buy orders that came in immediately push
price right back up yeah it went straight back up yeah the reason i didn't get filled on my market order
long is i have a um basically it's like a limit if my order is slipped more than one pip it can't
sells the trade. Okay. Is that something you have to put into your settings? Yeah. Yeah. Okay.
Just automatic settings I've put on. So I tried to go long and it wouldn't fill me. It just comes
up with a rejection. Yeah. Anybody who went long essentially would have been slipped here trying to
find sell liquidity left over and that move down. There was almost none of it. And what's interesting here
is we had bid, bid, bid, bid, bid, right? Early in morning, bid, bid, bid, bid, bid, bid, and then
once that gave in and price sold off,
the sell liquidity started to hold price down here.
Did you get it?
So it didn't just,
it wasn't concentrated in this move.
It didn't follow along with it.
It actually stayed up here.
Right.
And the liquidity stays light,
even past the event as well.
All right.
So the market,
imagine like dazed,
you know,
a box that gets stays where you get hit in the fucking face,
you get your dazed for a bit.
The market essentially is smacked and it's dazed for a bit.
the liquidity is primarily to do with the lack of willingness to take on a directional position
in and after such an event.
It happens time and time again.
And then we had a few of these today.
We had multiple headlines, some were positive.
I think early in the morning, Boris Johnson, or at least there was news that said the UK will
continue past the 16th of October deadline, which is today.
There was a Brexit negotiation talk thing that had a deadline for Friday.
that's why the market was quite kind of like teetering before these days
so in the morning we had I caught that long by the way
we had a headline saying that the UK will go past
and you know continue to discuss the deal or whatever past today 16th
and then the headline came out and there was a few other headlines here
this one for sure was a headline and this last pop
was quite inefficient as well
I couldn't get filled on any of these
that's the problem
oh is it because of the spread
no it's how illiquid it is
if I'm a buyer I need sellers
I don't want to get slipped more than one pip
so if I'm trying to buy for example
10 lots down here
they just can't give me 10 lots at the price I want it
yeah they'd be willing to give me 10 lots
somewhere here for example
you don't want that
so nobody wants to go long 10 pips away
from where they've entered at least an accurate day
trader precise day trading um so i'm kind of willing to like say you know it's better not being filled
on the trade and getting slipped but obviously that's just a problem with trading not even big
but trading under these super super super illiquid points in points in time they always come after an
event the market's most liquid in response to a illiquid sorry in response to a surprise event like a
headline and the market already like imagine we're expecting news but we don't know what it's
going to be yeah so already there's a lack of willingness in the market to like directionally take
on huge bets which we've seen all day right after this event here after the headline really
the market just dried up and you can see towards the late later end of the day the volatility
is just contracted is doing hardly anything um it's low volume basically you've been low volume for
the last three four five six hours but it's been nice in the sense that you have the
He's didn't move to getting filled.
I caught some nice trades early on.
I caught a small move here.
Had to cut it for pretty much nothing.
Couldn't catch this high because there's no level on the left.
It's just been one of those days.
Although it's hitting the levels quite well,
just not getting filled because it's too illiquid.
What about that one up top where 1.29619?
I was on the flipping shower, man.
I'm so pissed at that one.
I'm so pissed.
that would have made you a week for sure that one 100% wow that level I know I know I wouldn't
I would not have been able to unless I had to take profit here
price would have come back on me way too quick yeah but that's three seconds it's
sold off and you're thinking three seconds under like yeah that's three minutes later
actually I probably would have cut it anyway you know at that stage there there's no
difference between 90 pips and fucking 60
pips. Your stop loss would have been very, very
small as well. Always past
the level. If that's the level
my stop loss is past it.
Now, just to let you know, just because I have these
levels doesn't mean I'd trade oil. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Yeah, you told me, you told me.
It's more just marking
out areas where I deemed it to be
liquidity, we know liquidity access
friction, and then it depends on how
price approach that liquidity. Yeah, so if it comes
in very inefficiently, then
that's the basis for it, I guess. That's like
the basic parameter, but things like inefficiency is a spectrum. You can have extremely inefficient
and you can have extremely efficient and anywhere in between. So depending on which end of the
spectrum we're on and what kind of variation of inefficiency is, etc. Sometimes a move like this,
you have to, sorry, I move like that, you can take responses almost on every new extension out
will respond. So here's a high price extends out.
It becomes super, super inefficient.
The volume dries off.
The liquidity is down there
and price subsequently has to reach back down to pick it up.
In this kind of relatively efficient environment,
you can take response.
You can close your eyes and take a trade will work.
Then there's other times, let's just look at.
Yeah, something like this, yeah?
So take for at least 60 minutes, I think.
Yeah, about 50 minutes.
You'll see in bidding.
With these type of moves, you have to time your train.
trade and we're looking at the characteristics of the move here we're looking at the characteristics
of the move here throughout its full duration trying to time and identify the exhaustion point
but we're going to discuss those characteristics over the next few sessions so yeah that's
what cable's been on um not a bad week for yourself then we're trying to trade in man fucking
yeah it's just same old same old isn't it did you have did you have um any time to to look
over the
Yeah, I've had a glance
at it actually
I was going to ask you
to go through it
some stuff I want
to talk about
I didn't really want
to put you know
the dealer behavior
back on it
because that
Yeah, it's cool
midflow
that's in my
Midflow is just a
so we've already
gone through the dealer behavior
I have it creates
those inefficiencies
it results in FX
running further than it shot prices
they're a bit more spiky
than they should be
and a lot of these
legs away from
the areas of stability are super, super inefficient.
That's what happens as a result of dealer behavior and a microstructure.
But when we're discussing mid-flow, we just took, that's following on from that,
where in effects there's multiple, or in trading, there's multiple different types of environments.
And we're looking at one specific environment of imbalance and what's going on within that imbalance.
So, you know, why does price hold these bases on the way up?
What's going on?
Well, there has to be by liquidity there, stop in any market order sales,
from pushing through.
Simultaneously, there has to be
less sell liquidity in a way
and market order buyers are pushing
to the less liquid side. That's the only reason
buy bases will hold
and price will go in
this kind of structure. So we look at the reasoning
or the liquidity state
behind these type of environments.
It's critical because in that environment,
you can't really look for huge trades
in either direction you'll come to find.
In midflow.
In midflow. It's not that
conducive to be looking for huge trades. You can't trade with the trend, definitely. Depending on
the time frame of the move as well, it can be a bit easier to trade with the trend. But
putting it quite simply, one side of the market's weak, one side of the market is strong.
The best entries typically down at the origin, if you've missed that, you're not really getting
big pullbacks to get on board with. So if I had to buy this, where does my stop go? It has to go past
here. It results in a huge stock. There's a bigger margin for ever.
or like there's a bigger risk of price going to me sitting in draw in drawdown compare that to
taking precise entries at the point of exhaustion you are the probability of price going
your way is skewed is almost guaranteed if you're catching the exhaustion point correct do you get
it so here I'm relying on strength in the market and that bi-liquidity is actually present
here I don't need to rely on strength yeah you get it I don't even need
a lot of market order buying to push price up
I could technically have more selling
than buying and price would still go up anyway
because price goes to a less liquid side
so trading under a condition of exhaustion
which is created why is that skewed book where this
inefficiency why is that skewed book where there's
weakness on one side created as a result
of the microstructure behaviors we've discussed
or as a result of the microstructure and the participant
behaviors we've discussed I was going to say it seems like
these um the midflow levels on exactly like the best to trade off are they it's just a
completely different environment yeah um you don't really get huge pullbacks in any direct so that you can't
i'm not saying you can't trade with the trend it's just within midflow you're not getting these
huge pullbacks to sell into you're having to aggressively accept selling up more and more expensive
prices or embellish midflow you're having to buy it higher and higher prices it's kind of and
it kind of goes against buying low and selling high.
But this is my personal preference.
Over time, you'll find, because we're going to test it,
I'm going to get you to test it out,
that trading at the thinnest point in liquidity
is where there's highest certainty
or where there's the most skewed probabilities.
So if I was talking about it in a hypothetical scenario,
let's just say at the point of exhaustion,
where the cell volume is dried off
and the cell liquidity is thin,
times by a bit of thickness and by liquidity
is 100% guaranteed price will go to the less liquid side
on any bi-order.
As soon as price responds,
that by volume shot can quite easily start to dry off
and the probabilities of price continuing immediately
slowly start to depreciate.
So at the point of exhaustion is where you have the highest probability
of the initial response.
And then as soon as price moves away from it,
the probabilities may be still skewed in going and continuing higher,
but they're not 99 to 1, let's say, anymore.
They can be quite easily more balanced to 60, 40.
And also a lot of the time,
we're going to have some inventory left over in this move of the move down,
which again means that immediate continuation at this particular dot
is not 99 to 1 anymore.
Yeah, it's the same as, you know, that one that,
you said when we was on the session
when you said price is going to go up from here
and it went up to like 4R
you did say that
it came into a little inventory
and then it came back down and you did it
because you didn't say the same thing that you're saying
now yeah yeah
we're going to talk a bit more about inventory
today but
the point I making is
whenever there's 50 50 probability
or 60 40 or 70 30
apply that over a large sample
so something is 70 30
70% chance of win
and 30% chance of losing
take that bet a million times
you're going to lose 30, 40 times in a row at times
100%.
So me personally, I don't really like to trade
in these conditions
I want to be trading in the most
favorable types of environments
or the favorable instance,
favorable instance, for me personally
that's trading at the point of exhaustion.
Over time and experience, I've found that
the exhaustion first touch of a level
is the highest probability, the second touch to retest on a level of frequency, they fail more
frequently than the first touch does.
Also, trading at the point of exhaustion, immediately you're likely to get a response,
which puts you in a bit of profit initially.
We can use that profit as a bit of cushion to decide and to interpret if the following
a price action that comes after it is reflecting a winning trade or losing trade.
rather than buying let's say here
where there isn't skewed probably is anymore
it's a bit more balance it's a bit more 70 30
more likely to lose
you can still you know there's still all the variables
over time that we're going to look at which increases
the probability of taking this retest trade
but it's not as skewed as taking at the point of exhaustion
yeah right and if you take a trade here
you have no cushion of profit
there is no immediate price going in your favour
giving you a 7, 10, 8 pips, cushion of profit,
there is none of that.
You're hoping that buyers continue to buy,
whereas when I'm taking the trade,
I just need exhaustion for this short period of time.
If you buy here, you need buyers there,
you need buyers there,
you need buyers to continue and continue and continue.
So you kind of need probabilities to remain favorable
for a longer period of time.
I just need probabilities to be favorable,
i.e. exhaustion, thin move
for a relatively short period of time.
Yeah, that makes sense.
And all I'm talking about is getting an initial manageable response.
The key word is manageable.
Because what I don't want to do is take an entry,
have a huge stop or a relatively bigger stop
than taking the first touch,
which increases the likelihood of me having to spend time in drawdown,
i.e. being in the negative on that position.
When you're in the negative, I found it's about,
bit harder to like try and assess probabilities whereas taking out the first touch having that
caution of profit you can relax a bit and let the trade play out and you can focus more on
the characteristics of you know how price is unfolding again all of these things is necessary for
you to validate not just take my word for it I'm going to give you a way to actually engage price
and then you'll be you'll be forced to validate them or invalidate them anyway through your
experiences but don't just take my word for it if I'm saying trading a
the thinnest point is more favorable, test it.
See how it works.
And it will be in a pretend demo kind of type of environment.
So you aren't ready to be exposed to trying to make money or not.
So, yeah, trading away from the point of exhaustion,
you need probabilities to remain favorable for a longer period of time.
Trading at the exhaustion point, you need a relatively short period of time
where there's just exhaustion for that time.
Yeah, we have a very cushion.
Yeah.
But yeah, the keyboard here is manageable response.
we're looking for conditions or price features,
combination of, you know, combination of price features,
or you can call it confluencer features,
which all increase the probability of price responding initially,
so much so that we can then manage the trade from that standpoint.
It's where you have the lowest risk.
If I'm trading at the point of exhaustion, in my opinion,
you have the lowest risk because that's a thinnest point.
It takes much less buying to push price up.
The probability of price or your,
your trade spending a long time in drawdown is not that high,
that doesn't mean you will execute perfectly at every exhaustion point,
and nor does it mean that you will success, you know, where you think is exhausted,
it doesn't mean necessarily you're going to be right.
However, the trades that are actually, you know, at the thinnest point,
and you're buying into them, for example,
they will almost immediately move in your favour.
The trades that are not at the exhaustion point,
the characteristics are going to be completely separate and different
so much so that you can differentiate between the two
just the same way you can differentiate between
a black man and a white man right there's two very very different
characteristics in the skin color there's going to be very very different
visual characteristics in the in the characteristics of a winner and loser
over time we look to identify them and experience them
but it's essentially finding a combination of parameters
and price features behaviors parameters
they're all kind of related
which consistently
needs to a manageable response
from that standpoint
we have the cushion
to manage our trades
and leave it essentially
as long as the characteristics
remain favourable
leave the trade to work out
etc
it's much better for your psychology
as well isn't it
if you have much more of a cushion
I agree personally yeah
but it's not easy
you're going to make
you know you're going to use the wrong levels
trade selection
is always relative
to the kind of
environment prices in
if price is moving
a million miles an hour
that's not that fast
but if it's moving
super aggressive on one side
your trade selection
has to be tighter
you have to be a bit
more selective
with the levels you use
if it's a bit more
balanced
you can be a bit more relaxed
so again over time
you have to experience
the differences
in price characteristics
in essence
trading in those
environments taking trade using different types of levels in all various environments so you can better
determine what the most appropriate way to trade driven inefficient one-sided environments is like
and of course how you need to and what you can do in more balanced environments as well yeah so that's
just building experiences in trading different types of environments then after that you have to
start assessing the environment in real time because here we're looking at historical examples
you have to be able to assess an environment as it's unfolding
so we're looking at the smallest of details in price
we're attracting information wherever it's present in price
from movement the way prices moving
the types of levels price is responding off
the duration of price runs
the times of day prices move in
all of these things combined
you're attracting information from that
to determine okay this is the environment
this is the types of behaviors we connect to that environment
you'll start to associate certain characteristics
with again different types of environments
It all comes down to whatever the environment is, this robust organizing principles that we use as a reference point to compare price against, right? So we know that price moves to the less liquid side. For example, that's one of the organizing principles. So if I'm seeing a directional move, which is being bid quite aggressively for a period of time, it's relatively, you know, first of all, you don't want,
I hopefully can see these moves quite early on through introspection,
sorry, not introspection, through a building of skill,
through building experiences, etc.
I've seen it happen so many times.
I know the characteristics have driven moves,
so I can recognize them quite early on.
That's like the skill part intuition.
But outside of that, outside of recognizing when it's happening,
if there is a price move that's continuing in one direction for a period of time,
it doesn't make sense to be a huge, huge seller.
in that environment. So long price is showing characteristics of buy basis holding, which is
by liquidity is present, holding price up, and obviously weak sell liquidity. In each of these
instances, yeah, price will draw back in, but the pullback's going to be shallow when it's super
driven in one direction. In that environment, you don't want to be taking basically weak levels
on the left. We'll define what weak levels are. You really only be one thing to pick strong
origin type core areas of liquidity
and then if I'm trying to time
the end of this trade or this trend
if I want to counter the trend
and I want to basically fill it back down
we also need to be looking for weakness
inside of the move which starts to tell us that
the buying momentum is slowing down
right so the liquidity that's heavily aggressive
on one side chasing price
and holding price off at every single junction
but looking for characteristics within that
within the price
which give us insight into
the most recent changes
in the tempo, the rhythm, the momentum.
So it's all, never prediction,
it's not necessarily predicting
with the market it's going to be
two, three days down the line.
Really is anticipating what price,
not anticipating, but it is assessing
what price is doing now, what the current state
of liquidity is against the reference points
of experiences that you've built.
So you've seen these different types of environments
before you validate them, you understand what's happening behind the candlestick,
and what the implication of all these things are, like I just said.
If there's heavy ones out of liquidity, you don't really want to be short in that environment.
You don't really want to be looking for big shorts.
So all said and done, rather than making long-term price predictions,
we're assessing current price action, anticipating the most favorable areas where price might
respond as a result of, again, the organizing principle.
So when price goes to the less liquid side, we also know that,
as a result of dealer behavior
liquidity can stay
price move can run away
seeming as if it's strong
but in reality it's just a function of sell liquidity disappearing
in response to volume shot creating weakness in the market
right and if one did want to
if you did want to
you know fade a price run
if you did want to fade a move
that's moving in one direction in a strong way
you would know exactly
when and where is highly likely to move in your favour.
So we wouldn't necessarily be looking for sellers to maintain this position here.
Actually, after this did move, where prices expanded out away from the inventory of liquidity,
that's where there's higher probability of buyers drying off and price something to draw back in.
If you wanted to trade against the trend, for example.
So understanding in what dynamic or the current environment price is in,
And then the types of behaviors we see in that environment, you can then build out appropriate ways to engage that environment, how to trade it, which exact places you want to be trading in, how to time your trades, the characteristics at which, you know, which you're trying to exploit, variable volume flow, buyers dried off, buyers dried off, buyers dried off, buyers ride off, buyers ride off.
Not once did this, it did any high retest hold. Not once.
you have a high price came back to it no retest it actually pushed past it then dried off you have a high
price pushed past it the retest did not hold then dried off in each of these instances where price did
push through it became relatively inefficient right yeah so if you are trying to trade against
the trend of this environment based on the characteristics we know why these highs I'm holding
it's not because the strong sell liquidity that this high was put in it's more to do with
the buy is exhausted the price run out the bid's got super super super thin where it didn't even take
a huge level of sell liquidity to push price down because the real buy liquidity holding the
price run up is down the inventory are you following me yeah yeah right so um these highs don't
really have a lot of sell liquidity that's likely going to hold price and push price down it's
not the reason that high is being put in is not because of strong selling it's exhaustion two very
very different types of price reasons for why price moves now in that event or in that circumstance
we're consistently seeing the highs failed to hold price extend pass dry off exhaust and then draw back in
price returns to that high there isn't enough sell liquidity there price pushes through dries off
draws back in so again if you wanted to trade this environment you know the most obvious
way to look for trades is wait for the extension as it becomes thin and then try to
to push it back into range.
That's one reasonable observation
in trading this environment.
Why is price drying off here?
So why are we seeing this behavior?
If this is a buying market,
it's not a trick question.
If this is a buying market
and there's one-sided buy liquidity,
this relatively thinly dispersed sell liquidity,
why is then price going against the strength?
Yeah.
In this environment where we have strength
on the bids and buy liquidity,
why is then price selling off
if it's a bullish environment
oh so yeah so at these points
where price has moved inefficiently
it's not really
it wasn't moving inefficiently
no no why it wasn't moving inefficiently
you said it's moving inefficient at these points
why was it right so
let me pull up a whiteboard
actually it probably better if we look at proper price example
so do we agree that these
these areas here are inefficient
so that
yeah that
that that why are they
becoming inefficient
due to dealer behavior
specifically why are they behaving that way
they're removing the buy liquidity in the market
no
so you're a dealer
there's heavy heavy heavy
buy liquidity in the market yeah
I come
to you and I ask you to provide me
by liquidity, would you say yes or no?
Why would I need buy liquidity?
What am I a seller or a buyer?
Oh no, no, no, you need it.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, you'd have to be a seller.
Okay, so I'm selling to you here.
Are you going to remove by liquidity
or give me a much as I want?
Yeah, remove it.
No, you wouldn't.
Well, on the move down?
No, in this whole environment.
Forget these points here.
You said there's a move removing bi liquidity.
That's not why this move is inefficient here.
no yeah
so in that instance
is removing sell liquidity
from the market
okay
so what do you mean
by removing sell liquidity
I just want to validate
that you know
what you're talking about
so so basically
he doesn't want to
take on the risk
of being
short in the market
when there's information
that's coming in
so there's buy volume
coming in
they already have information
much more information than me and you
that there's weakness in the market
on the sell side.
Because if they sell here
they need to buy it back off another seller.
The likelihood of them buying back off another seller
without losing is quite high
because the seller is thinly dispersed.
It's only thin.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Right?
So that is the reason why, right?
Price is moving out super, super inefficient here
because already there's thick bids,
very, very thick bids market wide.
Yeah.
And there's relatively thin offers.
let's just say here when that market order buy comes through at the right time at the one dealer
that dealer decides to not take on that risk because you know he'll get clipped so he avoids
taking on short positions yeah that's like just avoiding adverse selection insurance companies
they make sure you know they check your health or they check your age of his car insurance
they check your previous you know crash as well you know how many claims you've had in the past
because they're trying to limit their risk the same with the dealer they don't want to take on a short
position because they won't be able to hedge out without taking losses price will move against them
high high likelihood so they avoid taking on short positions other entities you know they might
aggressively try to capture the buy liquidity and then resell it a bit higher dealers also will take on
any long positions so anybody who shorts to them here as price is moving up anybody who's showing to
them they'll take that position on and be able to then resell it back in in the form of liquidity
yeah so raising in inventory and controlling the supply of liquidity exactly so raising inventory no but definitely controlling the supply of liquidity okay so so what's the difference between raising inventory and we'll discuss it okay we'll discuss why inventory rises in a minute and what inventory tech specifically is but the point I'm making is the market you know technically the purpose of the market is to facilitate trade so here the market is doing quite well
Buyers are finding sell liquidity, sell market order sellers are finding bi liquidity, price remains stable.
It's typically because there's not that much volume pushing in any direction.
But still this stack by liquidity in this instance, in this whole area,
and it's still relatively thin cell liquidity in this area.
As soon as that volume shot comes through, just imagine a gap being created here.
Or the sell liquidity was already bought, bought, bought, bought, so there wasn't any sell liquidity at that time.
and it quickly any buy volume shot caused price to run out the dealer behaviors kicks off it compounds the move essentially makes it worse stretching out stretching out stretching out stretching out the willingness to buy up here is almost nonexistent yeah the real buy liquidity remains down here because that's where the market is facilitating trade that's where volume wants to transact that's where liquidity wants to transact price only diverged or distorted away from
this value area, the range,
is because the dealer behavior,
just avoiding adverse selection,
then everybody else responding,
the market becomes inefficient.
It's not finding sellers for buyers.
Sellers are actually running away.
That's more costly for buyers, no?
It's less willing than the market here
to continue buying, buying, buying.
Actually, that volume shot,
it gets filled in small pieces,
it gets stretched out like a chewing gum,
it leaves gaps and breaks
in terms of where the orders were filled.
eventually when the volume dries off
you have like a vacuum
hardly any liquidity left behind it
you get it yeah
so
there's less liquidity left on the buy side at that point
isn't it exactly on the way up
hardly any bi liquidity built up
the bi liquidity stays here
but mostly hardly any bi liquidity builds up
so yeah think of it like as the market
is stretching out here the liquidity is thick
and then it stretches,
stretches,
eventually when the market order
driving volume,
buying volume,
dries off,
again,
it doesn't take that much
to push price down.
Cool,
perfect.
So now we're explaining,
that's your explanation.
You said dealer behavior,
I know you did,
you were right,
but I want to know
why the dealer
is avoiding adverse selection.
We discussed it.
They don't want to take
on your position because it's risk.
It's highly likely
the price will move against them.
They're taking advantage
of information they know
and they're using it to the benefit.
everybody will do that if you knew that tomorrow the UK interest rates are going
rise you'd be a buyer of the pound for example um so yeah this dynamic of deal
avoiding adverse selection it creates price and it causes price to move out super super
super inefficiently and dry off and have to come back in to build up and find buy liquidity again
before it takes on this next move runs out dries off and it has to come down to find
by liquidity before his next move so if you want to be short in this environment it doesn't make sense
to trade in the area of balance sorry if you want to be short in this you know if you want to short this
trend or if you're looking for a way to trade it the characteristics are really really
simple and visual you know visually present buy base holds the buy base held
price moves out
their high retest does not hold
price goes
extends past it
and I know you can class this as high highs
and higher lows but we're not
you know we're actually looking at how it moves
from areas of stability
becomes super super thin here
the probability of price coming back into range
versus continuing out of the range
is much higher
probability that price will come back in
is much higher than it continuing to get
bid, bid, bid, and buy liquidity, except super expensive prices irrationally, it's just very
unlikely to happen, all right? In FX. Yeah. So in that condition then, you know, you're looking
for ways to trade this environment and describing the visual characteristics and why they exist,
then you can make logical deductions on how you want to approach this in the future. If you want
to go short in a bullish midflow scenario, you wait for extensions that are, you know,
at the exhaustion points, extensions, not retests.
of the high but extensions
past the highs
extension past the highs
where it's very
very likely you'll get
there's a high probability
of price drawing back into range
now that might not necessarily
be the biggest of moves
but it's a higher probability
occurrence
right and that's just
within this one environment
where you said it's not that great
it doesn't look that great
to take advantage of it
I'm saying also I agree
but it doesn't mean
there is no trade in there
you can definitely trade
the behaviour of this move
you get it
the behavior is what's consistent
the behavior is consistent
regardless of if Goldman Sachs is the biggest buyer
here and they're buying
500 fucking billion over the next five days
for their client
you could have a multitude of hedge funds
you can have four hedge funds
that they decide to go long the pound
for whatever reason I don't give two fucks
about them I know price will dry off consistently
they can't stop the market from behaving
the way it is
for two main reasons
reasons. It's too liquid to control it in this kind of way. It's way too hard to manipulate
something as liquid as this. Think of it as a large ocean. You can't really push the ocean around.
Yeah. You might be able to cause a few ripples here and there. You cannot fucking control
the ocean. It's just way too vast and big. And what we're seeing here are the small ripples
and waves. Do you get it? Now, yeah, so regardless of who's buying this, for whatever reason
they're buying it, the
organizing principles will remain
the same. Price will go to the less liquid
side. You can
to a high degree of probability
predict that
dealers will continue to behave the way they will
because if they want to remain profitable, they have to
avoid taking on losing positions.
They have the necessary
technical infrastructure, the technology
basically to do that.
But at its essence,
everybody who's trying to make
money or fucking speculative transactions
or at least market making,
they have to avoid that.
The worst, the biggest enemy for a market maker is a moving market.
Because they can't capture the spreads
without price moving against them.
Yeah.
Right.
So these behaviours are always going to occur.
It doesn't matter who's buying a selling.
So here, look, this is a much more driven sell-off.
You can just imagine there was much less buy liquidity
and probably stronger selling as well, market order selling.
And the sell liquidity, so, you know,
the actual sell limit orders,
they were also likely moving down
rather than,
let's just say market order sell,
price run down,
the seller has dried off.
These sell limits are also moving down with it,
stopping price from,
for any buyers,
they quickly find sell liquidity
very, very close to price.
You get it?
So here's sell liquidity,
this week buy liquidity,
market order cell comes through
from a completely other market,
a client,
sets off the price chain mechanism,
price runs, runs, runs, runs,
until the sellers dry out.
Now, in this example,
where do you think the sell liquidity you moved to?
Let me just annotate.
What, the thick sell liquidity?
Yeah.
It remained.
Inven, yeah.
Yeah, it remained there.
No.
Why didn't then any buying push price right back up there?
That's the origin, though, isn't it?
Yeah, well, let me ask you.
you're saying that's where the thick sell liquidity is then in theory any buyers that come through
would not just easily push price back to the thick you know because buyers need sell liquidity
yeah well yeah these these floating algorithms they'll be moving their
limits down here so then once it be sell liquidity moving along with price i want to get down
yeah yeah yeah yeah so that's where the sell liquidity is at that time okay i thought you mean
like what's like the thickest point oh sorry sorry yeah
probably just a miscommunication,
but the sell liquidity is moving along with price,
right?
The point I'm really trying to make is,
in this instance,
can you see how price runs short pull back?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Runs, short pull back,
runs relatively short pull back,
here, short pull back.
That's because the sell liquidity
is moving from here down with price.
Yeah, yeah.
So price moves down,
the sell liquidity also moves down with it.
Right?
moves down, the sell liquidity moves down with it.
Compare that, compare that to this scenario
where price moves up,
where the buy liquidity doesn't move up that, you know,
as aggressively, actually remains back down here.
You follow me?
Yeah. So, in this instance,
looking at this down move, what if the selling liquidity
didn't move down with price and they remained up here?
Then you'd see a reaction when you come back to it up here?
Nope.
let me explain
all right so we're you know
so here is sell liquidity
price ran down market order sell
market order to sell
lack of buy liquidity
the sell orders dry out
where is the next part of buying
going to push price to
or any buying going to push price to
it would be higher than that wouldn't it
where
wouldn't they go further up to try and look for it
no no you're missing a point
the sell liquidity here
at this green line
yeah yeah
they'll sell liquidity there
let's just say 20 million
and there's bi-liquity here
of only
3 million stretched down over these dots
a market order
sell comes in for 2.9 million
price goes down no
yeah
the 3 million fills price
the 3 million by liquidity
it filled sorry that the market order
selling
price moved down inefficiently
so it left behind
thin sell liquidity.
When the next market order
buy comes through, where is
price likely going to go to find the sell liquidity?
Yeah, back up here.
To where?
Yeah, this area, yeah.
I can't see your arrow.
Oh, yeah, cool, cool.
Exactly. It's going to go find the sell liquidity, yeah?
So, price went back up.
Found sell liquidity.
Volume dries off again because variable volume flow.
Yeah.
20 million.
And then let's just say there's another market order
the sell shot price runs down yeah and let's just say the cell liquidity remained here the market order
cells dry off it leaves behind a thin illiquid area of price of vacuum where do the next market order
buyer is pushed price to back down to there okay the exact same thing happens crime builds up a bit
and then shot price runs out again where are the next oh yeah sorry the cell liquidity remains back in
this range, where's the market order
buyer is going to push price to?
Fini liquid moves. Right back up here,
now? Yeah. Can you see how
the polar backs are bigger because
the sell liquidity isn't moving down as
aggressively? Yeah. Staying
back at the previous range. Yeah, yeah.
Now, let's
look at a different example. Clear
views, drawings. Let's say
in this instance, this 20 million sell
liquidity. Oh, let me just get
a bit of mine as well.
Sorry, I don't know.
Okay.
So the same scenario, 20 million sell limit orders, 3 million by limit orders, market order sell for 2.9 million pushes price down, right?
But the sell order wants to get filled within a short period of time.
I want to get filled ASAP.
So this 20 million moves down here.
Where is price going to pull back to?
Same thing happens.
Price sells off.
Next market order sell.
This sell limit order.
So these sell limit orders, push hold price down here.
So you're just giving the answer.
You know, sell liquidity moves down aggressively.
holds price down here. Can you see how to pullback so much shorter?
Yeah, yeah. So this is when the limits are getting pulled with price, isn't it?
In both instances, the limits are getting pulled in price. This is more intense and more aggressive.
Okay, yeah, yeah, yeah. Right? The sell liquidity is accepting lower and lower and lower prices more
aggressively compared to the original scenario. The price sells off. The sell liquidity from here
does not move down the price. It actually holds back at the range and prices have to come from.
find it or buys if they come find it and then the sell equity distributing here here here another
volume shot it doesn't come down and hold and you know it doesn't populate the book down there
it stays where it is you get it yeah so any buying causes price to come all the way back up
builds up and then so we essentially see more efficient more stable price action larger pullback
characteristics and then here we're seeing much shorter pullback characteristics much more
aggressive driven price
based off the intensity
at which the sell liquidity
is pushing along with price
both instances
the sell liquidity is pushing along
just here is a bit slower
here's a bit more aggressive
so this is the question
I was basically asking you
or the point I'm trying to make
see how price doesn't fully fill
back to this last area here
yeah yeah
it just holds down here
it's because the sellers are there
and they're moving with it
and they're following it
they're following it following it
typically those moves
they don't last as long
typically is the key word there
a good majority of the time
those moves do not last that long
before price starts to stabilize
but the point I'm making
is depending on the level of aggressiveness
in the midflow
we will either see short pullbacks
we will either see
hardly any pullbacks
can you see how price didn't come back here
just holds
or you're going to see
really really stable
efficient prices
you get it
yeah
in both in every single instance
here
by liquidity is following
is this what you refer to
as tempo or is this something else
yes
this is tempo okay yeah
here what you're going to observe
is short polebacks
it's not that conducive
to be taking extension fills here
because prices are fucking filling any extensions
right
the only extension fields you're going to get is
when the candle
breaks past here, it'll come back and book his
it. Yeah.
I'll just like pick it up and just
give it a small, like this.
We extend past as high, comes back,
it grabs it. We extend past as high, comes back,
it grabs it. No significant
real pullback. Whereas
here, the mark is really quite efficient.
Pops out, comes all the way
back here. You get it?
So we have to
well, basically we're going to look to assess this in real time
as it's happening. You don't want to
trade this the same way you would trade this.
Here, you can take shorts and longs.
Here, you don't really want to be short.
If you miss the low, you're fucking, you have to buy a breaker.
You have to be a breakout trader to catch this.
After the, after the breakouts already happened.
But in either case, both are midflow, no?
Yeah.
Both are midflow, both the direction of your driver, both is one-sided strength,
one-sided weakness.
It's just the levels of intensity and the tempo are different.
So that remains true.
but the characteristics are still the same.
By-basis are holding in every instance.
The apexes or aka the highs are not holding.
And still at the extension point, price does dry off.
It doesn't just buy, buy, buy, because volume does dry off.
It's just that equity comes up and holds up there, holds price up there.
So midflow, I'm literally defining the characteristics.
Keep note of them, write them down.
If you were to trade a bullish midflow then,
Which one of these more favourable for you to trade?
You can be long or short.
You'd want to be actively trading this, yeah?
So prices rising.
Where would you trade?
No, no, no.
Like, this is something that I want to be down here.
But not, that's fine.
Yeah, not anywhere here.
But the question I'm asking is, which one would you want to actively engage?
So like take trades, interact with it as it's moving along.
Oh, yeah.
Not ride it.
Yeah, this one.
Yeah, exactly.
Because it's more responsive.
the pullbacks are bigger the ranges are easier to discern and you know pick out there's actually
more volatility here if you think about it price up then down then up and down even though broadly
speaking each candle won't be moving that much right so each individual candle actually won't
be moving that much now i agree this is better to trade actively uh this is for riding
this two completely different styles of trading if you ask me you can
doesn't mean you won't catch
like trades that you hold on to
but for the most part
if you caught a trade here
let's just say with a six-pip stop
at the point of like
24 pips you should really be scaling out
you should really be taking some profit at the table
and then
you can then ride it higher
more for ego purposes
and making a bit of change on top
rather than trying to make a hundred off this trade
you're better off
getting something like this
and making 5R a pop
and getting 100 all that way
5R 7R
5 R 5 R
3 R 2 3 4 R loss
right
you're much much more likely
to build up
ours here
versus catching that one winner
riding it higher
to Kumbaya
then you catch a jet to Africa
you fucking go meet Mozambique's president
none of that shit is likely to happen
yeah no one would
keep the whole position on for that long either.
Nobody.
I don't care.
If you got decent size, then yeah.
Sorry, if you got decent size, then no.
If you got small size, then probably it's quite easy to hold on to it.
Right?
But yeah, I agree.
So you said initially an observation that midflows are not that great to trade.
They definitely tradeable.
The price behaviours are super, super consistent.
You know, as we've discussed, we know why price draws against the range.
for, you know, the weakness is created,
why price draws against the strength,
weaknesses created a result of deed of behaviour,
and we know volume is variable.
So the level of volume does it remain a constant.
Just because there was a 30 million shot here,
doesn't mean new 30 millions coming in
at every single minute, every single second.
No, it just doesn't work like that.
You can quite easily have periods
where there's hardly any volume being transacted
compared to the periods where there is volume,
being transacted.
Yeah.
Right.
So here,
hardly any volume
would be transacted.
It's overnight as well,
just the Asia range.
So yeah,
all of these
organizing principles
all create these
consistencies in price behavior,
which then we use
to determine and describe,
not determine,
but not describe,
sorry,
but to assess the different
types of price movements,
the different types of environments,
and essentially what it means
to trade that.
You just told me,
you'd want to trade a more efficient type of price run
because it looks more responsive
and you're getting bigger pullbacks.
The reason price is pulling back deeper
is the liquidity is maintaining back down
at the last base
rather than aggressively chasing price.
Yeah. Right?
So we're again discussing why this behavior exists.
Anyway, let's move on a bit.
I just have a point to make old inventory.
So when you say raising inventory, no, you can just call it a phenomenon where buying here leads to buying here and leads to buying here and leads to buying here.
It's as if that when selling happens, just observing it as a phenomenon, that it leads to more selling.
The question is why?
Why does this happen?
Why does this move continue to sell and sell and sell?
that one argument is herd behavior.
You ever seen a flock of sheep?
Yeah.
So when somebody sells,
everybody else wants to sell with him
and then everybody sells
and they turn into one big selling party.
Right?
That's one theory.
The other is a much more robust one.
Doesn't mean it doesn't happen,
but much more robust.
It happens in equities, a risk asset.
FX, an asset that isn't,
oh, sorry,
it's not even a fucking asset
class, bro. FX is just this channel,
a river that you use to access other asset
class. I'm in America.
I need to cross the river to Europe.
Well, FX is my fucking river.
Okay.
Right? I ride it to get across.
Yes, so the second idea
behind this is large orders need to
be, first of all, hidden, and for them to get
filled, they have to be split into small pieces
for them to hide.
Right? It's called meta orders.
Meta, literally,
meta order literally means splitting a big
order into small pieces. If I want to get 100 million filled, I don't want to buy it market order
because I'll just send the market mad. I don't want to put 100 million market limit, sorry,
I don't want to put 100 million limit order in full size because everybody can, well, the dealers
at least can see that. That information will leak to the dealers. They might then avoid taking
on sell liquidity, avoid providers sell liquidity. So when any other market order comes through,
it causes price to move away from where I want to buy.
Yeah, from what your limit originally is.
Yeah.
So you can really only split your orders to small pieces and fill them over time.
That's literally the liquidity problem, that large traders face.
There's always a balance between execution certainty, how quickly you're going to get filled and essentially cost.
So I think about it.
If I want to get filled a fucking sap, I go mark your order long.
But I'm paying with a higher cost because price slips.
Yeah.
Right.
If I hide my liquidity, so, you know, I only show tip of the iceberg.
I want to buy at this level.
I want to buy $100 million, but I buy it in one million pieces time and time again.
So nobody else can see or nobody else realizes, let's say, in a hopeful world.
Then my execution certainty is lower because price might move away before I fill my $100 million.
I might only get $30 million off, but my cost is lower.
but really you can balance the two as well
you can have a higher increased execution cost
so execution certainty
and still a relatively stable cost
through a floating algorithm
so when price moves up
your liquidity also moves up
but it doesn't aggressively
chase too aggressively
you get it
so we typically see these type of
movements as a result of
large orders being filled over a pip distance range
and like we looked at HSBC's algorithm
you can put in, you want an order filled
let's say 100 million
you want it filled over 30 pips
if it doesn't fill it within 30 pips
cancelled whatever's left over
you can ask them to do it aggressively
so it aggressively chases price
you can ask them to do it passively
or on a medium balance
you can also ask them to fill it in-house
which is less likely to get filled
that quickly
or you can ask them to fill it out on all the venues,
which might result in information leakage
and everybody basically scalping you
and causing price to move away from where you want to trade.
But in either case,
there's always a balance between execution risk
or execution certainty and cost.
These are the real, real life problems
that large traders or large orders face
that banks obviously provide these type of solutions to
and there's a whole, like,
that's where the technology side of things are going to play, yeah?
at least for nowadays in the last 10 years
execution based
automated execution
is that how long it's been in here for about 10 years
automated execution and FX first
like so when banks started to build these algorithms
that clients can fill their trades with
like an option that they were offering to them
it was around 2008
that's when they started to offer
actually I've got a timeline I'll show you
this is a research
paper by one bank
I just need to find it
oh it's not by it's fucking by ECB
the European Central fucking bank
it gives you a timeline
mid 2000s
execution tools beginning to be used by clients
you know how I said by how non-bank
market makers came into the market and they started to
reduce their spreads become more competitive
this all started to happen in mid-2000s
and then it seems
as if they're saying it became more
prominent the ALGO executions
more in focus
past 2014, 2015.
TCA is
transactional cost analysis.
If I'm a buy-side firm, I'm buying
equity. I'm buying
from one bank, two bank, three bank, three bank,
four bank. I'm looking at how expensive
it is to mesh these three together,
four together. If it's cheaper to
cut one out, if I get better execution
by trading with one bank, if I get better execution
with trading with three different types of banks,
because these guys do different, they deal
slightly differently, this guy might internalize 100%.
So they might keep volume 100% in-house.
This guy might do it 70-30.
70% in house, 30% out.
And the way these guys behave can again affect
the prices that this guy gets.
If the dealers can also identify who this is,
so it's disclosed.
Just like if you ring your bank, it's all disclosed.
They know who you are. It's not anonymous.
If the byside firm is trading on a disclosed basis,
then basically these guys may start to widen the spreads for him
if his order flow is toxic
or is causing losses for these banks, et cetera, et cetera.
So transactional cost analysis is outsourcing a third-party firm
to analyze how expensive the specific costs are
we're trading all of these banks down to like a micro-phorxic accounting type level.
You know what forensic accounts do, right?
They can fucking pull up your whole life history.
Basically, look up your whole loss.
Yeah, yeah.
It's a similar type of field.
And then automation is basically just doing everything on an automated basis.
If I'm a buy-side firm, I don't have people sitting there buying and selling.
I just have tech guys who oversee systems that have built or that we've built that then trade into the markets themselves.
Do you get it?
And then regulatory stuff is how banks have to abide by,
changes in global code, FX code, which is a code that all tier one banks abide by.
There's generic rules, not even generic, there's specific rules that these guys say that
they will take part in, but FX is quite hard to regulate.
So you can't really, you know, each transaction can't be checked.
These banks still do have leeway to kind of manipulate and blur the lines.
But they all say they won't use last lock in an aggressive way.
They all say they'll give you best execution, which means to give you the look.
they're not to fuck you over
which is true
at least on a bank level
they're not trying to fuck you over
however the guy on the
you know if you're ringing into the bank
and there's a bit of a dickhead there
that isn't being right you know
nobody's overseeing that individual
he might start to do a madness
so you know if
when it wasn't so automated
I would ring into the one bank
and the teller or the sales guy
the guy at the desk
he would give me a bit of a last quote
he before you know i might tell him fill me a hundred million long
before he filled a hundred million long what if he told his other boy
to buy a hundred million first and push price up and then this guy starts buying after
yeah he can cause it more yeah it's front running basically
they stop this basically by increasing the regulatory
i guess control over these banks
there's much more scrutiny you can't do that as much anymore
as early as
there was this guy
Anthony Creel I think his name is
he worked for society
no not this nigga
society
society general
London
Creole some
some motherfucker like this yeah
I swear his name is Creole
oh Jerome Curveill yeah
yeah
this motherfucker
he is an arbitrage trader
his job
was to take advantage of the price
difference between a cash contract and a futures
contract or a cash asset and a futures asset
basically there's a price difference and his job was to arbitrage
oh he lost 7.2 billion
well that's his job to arbitrage
it's guaranteed money you know you 100% make money
this is in 2007 or 8 or 9 or 10
one of those years the markets were crashing let's say it's 2008
the markets were crashing Dow Jones selling off
S&P 500 selling off
Dax selling off
which is the German index
The 30 largest companies in Germany
That's the index of them
This guy thought that the Dax is oversold
So every night
Everyone, everybody went home
He would stay behind
And he would place long positions
And start buying up the German Dax
So what happened is
Think about it as in Beres-Midflow
Price in Bairish mid-flow
Sellers would dry off because everyone's going home
Yeah
He would then slow
buy it up and because there's so much sell liquidity stacked in this book he hardly caused
the dent you get it yeah the sell liquidity here is way way way way way way too thick and he
was slowly buying it up then when when he finally gave in and went home the next day the market
would gap open down here you get it because he thought it's oversold he's trying to buy it he's trying
to push price back up he's trying to be genius oh did he not close his position
brov he over leveraged his short his long positions two times the marginal marginalization of that bank
that bank was worth that position overall i'm sure it was like 70 fucking billion he was exposed to
some mad mad mad number 17 billion how is he even allowed to do that exactly there was no
oversight his risk manager should have been down his fro they didn't clock it bro that's that's that's
How can you not clock that one of a guy on 66K a year is doing that man?
Don't quote me on 70 billion.
Oh, look, 1.5 times the market capitalization of that major bank.
Do you get it?
Bro, he's not even, he's not even like five figures and he's doing that much money.
There you go, 73 billion like I said, bro.
I knew I thought that number was the wrong way.
He's riskier thing he must have had it in his ass as well from people above him.
for sure he went to jail in it he went to jail but the point of making is you know
here it says that regulatory insight increased and whatnot whatnot this is one of those reasons why
because idiots like him nobody was overseeing him bloody look at his nose bro one side's
indented because he snips too much cocaine right he must have had to after that so yeah
what happened is this guy called navsing autistic yeah he worked out of
prop firm, Futex, every night at the end of the day, basically at 5, 6pm, he would see that
there's a, there's like a fish trying to swim against the tide. Think about it. The current is
strong. The fish swimming against it is only making, you know, little headway. Yeah. So when that
Anthony, this curvil guy is buying huge, huge amounts, one day they observed that that buyer, at the
end of the day he gives in the next morning the market gaps down so the next day they saw the buyer
there again the next morning he got down again the third day the buyer was there they went bald's deep
shore next morning they made hundreds of grand they did it again made hundreds of grand this was
the first time nav Singh made a million trading trading against him they didn't know the trading
against him. They didn't know why
someone's buying it every night.
They later found out that this guy was staying
behind after everyone went home
and over leverage it.
You should have gone home with everyone.
But yeah,
so can you see how like the behavior
was consistent here? The sellers dry off.
It was, you know, price stabilized,
relatively low volume, just this one idiot
pushing price up. Every morning
it would continue. The sell
liquidity was too thick. In an environment
where all the, basically the global economy is
crashing, it'd be heavy, heavy, sell liquidity in the way anyway.
Yeah.
So, yeah.
I don't know why you can buy really at that point.
When the global economy is crashing like mad.
Yeah, humans are irrational, man.
But nobody should be given that much money or have access to it.
That's why you need regulation.
But anyway, the point really to be made here is Nav Singh made his first million,
identifying consistent repeating patterns, at least on a short-term basis,
within price, and then taking advantage of it.
you know what navsing shorted it alongside his mate
they made like a hundred grand within the first few days
his mate then stopped thinking he doesn't want to lose that hundred grand
Nav Singh kept better in that hundred grand until he made a million
that's the difference between Nav and the other guy
this guy not only was he smart
but he had the biggest bollocks ever
how does a guy who lives in his mom's bedroom
makes 70 fucking million in a trading career
especially going up against his algorithms man
he battered them
brother he battered them
but
how long did he get put in prison for
he didn't go prison
they didn't go prison they gave him house a restaurant
yeah
actually you know what
he you know before trying
you always sit in prison for a bit
he sat in prison for a few months at least
but then they let him out
he started to cooperate with the FBI
yeah
what happened to the money that he
he made?
He got scammed out of it, apparently.
Oh, yeah.
I don't necessarily believe it,
but apparently he got scammed out of it.
Yeah, people were telling him
investments and he was just
plugging them with money and stuff.
Yeah, yeah.
But I don't know how much I believe that.
I do know that
autistic people are slightly...
He was autistic.
Well, in that sense.
Okay, okay.
Yeah, he's got Asperger's syndrome.
Quite autistic.
So, yeah, like, they're quite gullible,
in it?
so yeah
where was we
we can identify these
consistent rights behaviors
we know why they're occurring
and then we can
take advantage of them
specifically in midflow
anyway
inventory
is where large orders
have to be filled
over a period of time
so they split to small pieces
and we basically
see it happen this way
so I'm going to explain
this price move
this one here
okay
prices run up
fuck it
you know we'll start with this
and you see there's an area of stability there
price runs out on market order selling price draws back
grabs the liquidity
yeah in essence it
grab probably is a misnomer
the sell liquidity is actually moving there
causing price to hold there
get it it's not necessarily grabbing it
but this is the inventory price draws down
pretty much feeds off it
forms a new area of inventory
runs out comes back feeds off it
runs out, comes out, feeds back off it,
and it continues this pattern.
So here, it comes and grabs the bottom,
comes and grabs the top,
but never once breaking above it.
So, for fuck sake.
And then we continue to see this.
We continue to see it.
All right.
Now watch this.
Can you see how it's going lower,
going lower, holding the last range,
holding the last range,
and then finally push through.
Yeah.
Why did it push through here?
if previously sell liquidity was holding price down following price with it as price moved lower the sell liquidity moved lower with it in bearish midflow the sell liquidity's dick and the buy liquidity is weak no yeah so the last dealing range successfully holds this is the the last area the last base is this aka dealing range aka inventory also known as right so the last dealing range
ceiling range the last inventory continues to hold continues to hold continues to hold
what must have happened here to push through that last inventory the there wasn't
the cell liquidity wasn't moving downward price then but it was here now look there
it moved with it moved with it moved with it um would you say they removed the cell
liquidity it was weaker okay weaker definitely weaker because think of it this way
there's a huge order here's one hour charge and when I say one order this
doesn't necessarily mean a one algorithm was told to fill 500 billion.
It could be to fill the small amount here and then a new order came and continued to fill it.
So just let's say for argument's sake, 500, 300 billion was transacted here,
which is reasonable over one, two, three, five, six, seven days, yeah.
It grabs some, it grabs, it grabs, grabs, grabs, grabs, grabs all the way to land.
It keeps picking it up.
It keeps delivering it.
It keeps filling that sell limit order.
Keeps filling it, filling it, filling it, filling it, filling it, filling it.
until finally in this region
there's little cell liquidity there
so you know
price goes to less liquid side it doesn't take that much
buying to push through
the last inventory
you follow me yeah
this then technically
is that not a change in the
intensity or the momentum
of the selling if previously all cell base
is held and that reflects
cell strength by weakness
yeah now now it's
broke out of it yeah
now it's broke the last inventory for the
first time, that's a technical
shift. Yeah, the environment
has changed now, isn't it? It's
basically giving a sign. This is what you call the
first sign of weakness.
If you want, F-S-W-O, if you want to
sound special. F-S-O-W,
sorry, for so.
But it's the first sign of weakness.
Or, you know what, keep it simple, first weakness.
We then,
you typically
basically see this area
get defended, right?
So there is some sell
liquidity here, but it
has to reach further to find
sell liquidity, where previously
it was only reaching very, very
it didn't have to reach that far back
and the sell liquidity was
there with it all the time. Here, the
sell liquidity is not with it.
Price has to reach, reach, reach, reach to find cell liquidity
and this is
first sign of weakness. You then
typically see the parabolic, aggressive
phase where
whatever
is left in the order is basically being filled
super super aggressively right and so you go from bearish midflow to your first sign of weakness
to then the parabolic phase yeah and then after that typically where you'll start to see
the reversal so i'm going to get you to look for that characteristic now here obviously price
didn't reverse that doesn't matter okay we didn't see major pullbacks here and then we went into an
environment of pretty pretty decent long-winded buying you could have had price breakout here but
probability changed so just because there's weakness here now doesn't mean you know just because
something basically probably is a dynamic it was favorable and the sell week there was sell weakens here
but you can have any new event come in at any given time which can change the probabilities but
within all price swings you're going to
to see these price features all price swings you're going to see buy basis hold buy a basis hold
buy basis hold buy basis hold and then you see here price runs runs through to new highs
breaks the last range there and then goes into a slightly more inefficient run yeah and then
price breaks down so you go from basis hold and basis hold and basis hold into your first sign of
weakness to the parabolic phase and then price
draws back in is that break up mid-flow which is giving us an indication initially that the
momentum in the move is drying off the parabolic phases which is basically there's an inventory
pushing along with price this 30 million is grabbed 1 million 2 million 3 million 5 grabbed etc
etc until that inventory let's just say there's only 7 million left all right price breaks
past have reached for it and essentially then this will get filtered into the market and drain this
area gets drained within this parabolic phase the market becomes super aggressive market order
buyers the seven million chases the seven million gets stretched out it's typically here
where the highest probability of exhaustion is okay all right so after the break of midflow
then into the parabolic phase but just because that happens doesn't necessarily mean that
it will reverse but you know probabilities right now do not necessarily have to remain the
same for the next you know for the future you can have high level of high degree of you know
likelihood that price would sell off and then down here the probability change again because
in markets at least they're dynamic new information is coming out all the time um any new
information can come out significantly and you know immediately change the probabilities
this is why a trade can be difficult you know we have to assess probabilities in real
time all the time we have to be able to spot the changes and probabilities in price
so we can update our we can update our views and our expectations but for now we're not
really talking about we're just validating that even on a microscale so this is a one
price run in itself that's inside of the large price run
which is also composed of loads and loads
and little price runs as well.
Now?
Up, down, up, down.
And then inside of this area,
you have multitudes of price swings.
That's another problem.
This price swing has nothing to do.
You know, basically there's conflicting scales.
They're crossing over.
You have this price swing.
And then you have the large price swing.
All of them doing the same thing.
I'll show you.
Look at that at the higher time for you want now.
so look we went into bullish mid flow here by base holds holds holds holds holds holds holds
holes that base holds this pushes price to new highs it holds it goes into a run this pushes price to
new highs price comes and breaks it for the first time yeah so pushes price to new highs pushes
pushes price to new highs, pushes price to new highs,
pushes price to new highs, breaks it for the first time.
We follow me.
And then we go into the parabolic phase and we drew back in.
We can have a look at a more distinctive example.
We're seeing bullish midflow here run by base holes.
Now, in this instance, this base held, even though we tested it multiple times.
This one pushed it to new highs
Price came back, fell to move
Came back deeper, still holding it
But then eventually did break through
And then now watch this
So you're seeing buy basis hold
Fuck sake man
Buy basis hold
Hold hold hold hold hold hold hold hold hold hold hold hold
Hold hold hold and then
Distinctive break here
Parabolic phase becomes mad and efficient
Whatever buy inventory was here is draining
It's picking it up picking it up
deep testing it and draining that whole area until there's hardly any bi-liquity left there
and then you get that parabolic shot where a huge amount of bivalent comes through
or more bivoli comes through creating this super super thin move
once that move is dried off this is going to be the only area left this is the last base
that pushed it to new highs basically yeah but still that whole area is weak
did you get it because you already drained this area
Okay, yeah.
We, you know, bi-liquity moved up, up.
There's bi-liquity here.
We grabbed it, bi-liquity there, we grabbed it, bi-liquity there, we grabbed it.
Price then runs past it, clears up whatever inventory is here.
Yeah.
And it literally is held in here whatever little is left of it.
Broadly, this area has been drained.
Wash out, parabolic phase, as Price draws back in, you get your, the bearish mid-flow.
Now, I'll show you the same with this,
but then this down move.
So this is the March sell-off.
It's got OCD with this shit.
Go.
So inventory is the liquidity that moves along with the price run
as a result of meta-orders trying to get filled.
Big orders having to split the pieces down and have it to get filled.
Because liquidity chases along with price,
it creates this base holding structure.
Yeah.
Right?
And we know why price dries off at these lows.
Even though this sells strength in the last base,
We know why price is drying off down here because of variable volume flow and a move down,
moving away from where the real sell liquidity is, creating weaknesses on the way down as well.
But if we're looking at this move, so we started selling off here, base holds,
price pushes the new lows, pushes the new lows.
Can you see he's not even pulling back here?
Pushes to new lows, that didn't push the new lows actually.
So pushes to new lows, feeds off.
it pushes to new lows
doesn't pull back
pushes to new lows
right all the cell
bases are holding
and then
we get our first
break here
look
bases hold
base is holding
basis holding
price
realistically
we should have
held this
wait
wait wait wait
they pushed to new lows
that didn't break
technically
shit
that one didn't
I thought it did
you know
let have a look at this
what is the last base
in that
yeah that's what
looking at. I'm sure it broke
but I'll have to have a look.
That wasn't a clear break, you know.
The only one I could argue is that
we had a deep test here draining
this area. So there was
an inventory of selling liquidity there.
Let's just say there's 30 million there. It grabs it,
grabs it, goes to the top side
clearing that whole area out.
Yeah. But that's still not
a technical break. So
the only argument will be is that this
shitty low level here broke.
Price, but that
push price to new lows.
came back fed off it fed off it deep test so yeah now not all of these are going to be this
entirely clear to see that's why exercising comes into play you're gonna have you're gonna have
build your ability to see them but on a highly consistent basis we see this dynamic occur so
again you see in bi basis hold break distinctive break yeah parabolic phase and right back in
and even in this down move you see in cell basis hold
cell base is old
deep test the cell base there
price then breaks
distinctively
continues
it takes a while
but goes into the parabolic phase
back to the origin core
and then
takes on the next month
right so
based on the way price is moving
we can assess how strong it is
as a result of
the characteristics of midflow
think of this
this sold off 1800 pips
with all cell bases holding
at least on the
it's a H1 move really
on the H1
or the inventory sold
let's have a look
for another example
there's a good one
price
by the way
we're going to discuss this
at a later time
this is a midflow
if midflow is only
when it shifts out
so it starts to run out here
buy base hold
hold hold hold hold hold
buy liquidity is getting
picked up
it's essentially moving with price
holding you off
at all these areas
at the highs
it's trying off
time and time again
runs up
we end up
having a deep test
here
all right
now think about
so this pushed it
to new highs
after that
we didn't make
any new highs
so there was a new
inventory
this remained the inventory
okay
yeah
grabbed it
it didn't go to new highs
came back down
they go to new highs
so this is still
the inventory
the last base
that pushed
it to new highs
can't you see it says it here
all right
then it starts the breakthrough
now what we have to separate is
this is one price run
individually
individually inside the larger price run
just the same way
you have this price run here
but that has a price run from A
to B and back to A
inside of it
and if I was to look inside of here
I would see multiple repetitions of A to B, back to A, back to, you get it.
So you see consistently repeating price swings on all timeframes from monthly down to one minute
and they're crossing over so I can see them on one hour.
I can see the one hour swing.
I can see the daily swing.
I can see the one minute swings here.
They're all present on the same scale.
That adds a little bit of complexity.
You have to build your ability to differentiate between the swings, which is just done
through experience and we're going to discuss that.
But here, what we've seen is buy base holds, pushes price through, this starts to push
the new highs, this is an individual run itself, and that has its own price swing, that has
its own mid-flow.
By-base's hold, this pushes to new highs, it holds, it holds, doesn't break that last
inventory, continues, continues, it holds, so it, you can't.
cluster washed you know all right so you get quite an early break there price continues continues continues
we have another washout here last range holds last dealing range holds last dealing range holds last
dealing range holds washing we're going to basically these small levels again picked up deeply
and then we go into their parabolic phase it was quite an early break here technical break
or there's much cool
compare this technical break here
and the fact that this didn't run that long
I guess it did but 500 pips
to a price run that ran
1,800 pips
without ever breaking once
so typically what you'll see is
the price runs that aren't going to continue
for a long period of time
just like this one down here
it broke quite early on
it didn't continue for a long time
because the cell liquidity was drained in the move
this one had so much sell liquidity pushing along with it that you know it's an event-driven
environment there would have been huge amounts of sell equity it could continue for a long time
but because there's so much sell liquidity holds every fucking base it relentlessly holds every
base so you know the moves that are going to continue are super super strong they will hold all bases
moves like this is the last base price moves down hold the last base moves down hold the last base
moves down
breaks the last pace
that's your technical
sign of weakness
continues
wash out
that basically
the parabolic phase
and then reversal
this one
here
it breaks quite early on
continues
we'll talk about
this deep test
at a later point
but it's picking
the liquidity up
picking it up
and then it goes
in the parabolic phase
I will bet you here
if this individual
price run
this is also a break
It must become pretty complex when there's so many price runs happening at once and stuff.
Yes, I know experience solves it all.
Not too much of issue.
No, we didn't break the big inventory.
They only broke these small little areas there.
Because we have a separate price run here.
By-biz holds, buy-biz holds, buy-biz holds, buy-biz holds.
Price pushes to new highs.
And then we break that inventory.
actually it's not a clear example
this is though
broke parabolic phase
and we gave in so this price
run broke inventory here
anyway the point is
we have characteristics of strong moves
which is mid-flow by basis hold
almost
you know what
a vast majority of price swings
will break their last base
just like we did here
this is a price swing
up down
buy-base holes, buy-biz holes,
buy-biz holes, holes,
technical breaks
clearly broke to new highs
and then he gave in.
People will see that as a market structure break
but typically it'll continue after.
We see a
technical break here.
Now we're getting at a minor
microscopic. So you're seeing all
cell bases hold there, all cell bases hold.
This is the last one. Breaks it,
breaks it, goes into a parabolic
phase and you get your
reverse right so you know after the parabolic phase where um so let me just uh annotate it here
will there not be like a thick level of um liquidity to the left or anything yeah they will be
it doesn't have to be that thick but like in this instance it wasn't thick it didn't feed
price for a long time if there was a huge amount of orders here by them orders
let's just say, 100 billion,
it would have been grabbed.
Some would have obviously followed along with price.
Once that dried off,
as price returned there,
that 100 billion would have been holding price,
eventually causing price to shift out,
and then this would have been chasing price.
So if it's a strong level,
you can see in how price feeds off it.
Here, clearly not strong.
The only reason price moved up is why then?
Weakness in cell liquidity.
See that technical break?
Look, every single range that pushes price to new lows, every single inventory is holding.
Not one is breaking.
And then here you have your first break.
Price washes out, comes massively inefficient here.
And then you have your biggest pullback in the whole move.
After a whole morning of selling off, after the break, after the parabolic phase, you had your move up.
now the parabolic phase is quite easy to distinguish
is the brakes of mid-flows which can be quite difficult
because you have the conflicting scales
and sometimes like in this instance what you're seeing here
is every minor base is holding like this
and then you have a washout here and a technical break
so every single minor base is held so far
until this one
is the first one that breaks
but still it's above the last inventory
so really it's just draining
the buy liquidity your present here
and then you have another small one
price runs and it has a massively deep test
when the midflow is strong
you typically won't see price deep test areas
and then you have another
and actually then they push the new highs
but you have another area that was washed at least
and then you have your parabolic phase
at each of these price runs we're seeing parabolic phases prior to them we're typically seeing a sideways phase
these are the characteristics we're going to be looking out for it gives us a level of forecasting ability
so again look cell bases hold cell bases hold the hold the hold the hold the hold the hold the hold the hold
first technical break quite a big one right here's a large sideways massive parabolic phase
and then you have price draw right back right at least past
where the break of midflow happened.
Now, as you can see,
there's massive variations here.
There's one very, very, very subtle one.
There's one really quite clear one.
And it's, again, a spectrum.
It ranges from extremely visible and clear
to really, really subtle.
I'll give you an example,
I'll try to at least, of what I mean.
But basically the point of making,
the market is so wide and the types of price runs
and environments that exist,
they're going to be there are going to be variations
and over time
we have to experience them
build an ability to spot the difference
through refined experiences
until you like for me
basically I can do it
spot these things happening in lifetime
you kind of have to build your ability
but yeah we will be going through
a structured process
on how it happens how you need to do it
I don't leave you to like just learn yourself
there is a followed or structured process
they have to follow
What, in order
When it comes to
The learning
Yeah, building your ability
What the fuck is this man
It's not infractors
What the fuck could it be there
There's one picture
I'm trying to show you
I just can't find it
Must be here
There we go
There's a very clear face
A really subtle face
There
I think that's Gandhi or someone
Yeah, it looks like Gandhi
doesn't it
and then there's an extremely subtle face.
Yeah, I didn't even clock that before.
Yeah.
In other case, the one made out of twigs.
This one, just the random drawing, yeah?
A similar kind of dynamic applies.
It is a bit gay to do that,
but a similar kind of dynamic applies
with these price swings.
Over time, you'll just become so intimately connected with them
when you're tracking them.
The parabolic phase will stand out to you.
The midflow stage will be super clear.
Even the ticking, how the candles form.
They're completely different here.
in even like you have a more stable move for all the biases holding logical
backs technical break there yeah whereas in this move it's all inefficient and it's a bit
clearer to see the break and this one is higher time frame inefficient so on a 15
minute one hour this would be inefficient much much less clear right but we have a small
break there so it's all about building your ability to see them
minor nuances in price there's a very simple solution to the problem you said of does not become
complicated or complex when there's multiple scales at play is very simple the solution for it is to
view the price swings relative to the time frame that they're present on or view them independently
each price swing has the same features just like everyone's face unless you're deformed has a nose
two eyes,
but there can be
slight variations
between them.
You can have a big nose.
You can have
a,
you know,
fucking,
what do you call this?
Eyes,
lazy eyes.
Visually,
anatomically,
they're the same.
Two eyes in the same place,
nose in the same place,
two ears,
mouth, teeth,
et cetera.
Yeah.
The anatomy is the same.
It's still variations
between them.
The same applies with this.
There's variations between them.
You will intimately
connect with,
you know,
using this
kind of structure essentially i'm giving you insight basically and how it can bring the level of forecasting
ability explained through the prism of what you know liquidity dynamics why is it weak we're seeing
a large order holding price down in the last dealing range and then once the momentum in that order
once the size of that order is being depleted it's essentially weaker we then typically tend to
see price pull back past it here it drains that whole area of liquidity
washes it out
and efficiently
into a parabolic phase
is basically
going to be
certain different types
of execution
algos that kick in here
that look to fill
the final order
or final part of the order
quite aggressively
it results in the parabolic
phase
and then you have
your largest move
time and time again
here is probably
a bit more of a subtle one
you have high
break
we call this a shift
when it does this
we'll discuss later
why but sell basis hold
sell bases hold
but inside of that
you wouldn't have spotted
that push price to new lows and that's your break
quite a break for an early
break and then you have
another price pushes to new lows
and another break
yeah
all right will that be present under one minute
okay push it to new lows
break
And then parabolic phase
And then here
What we're seeing here is this price run
Has its own break of midflow
And its own parabolic phase
All right
And then we obviously get the bigger move
The move back up
Where is the break in that midflow
On the last one? You know you said the one minute one
Here
Cell basis hold
Sell basis hold everything you want
I'm sure you're going to take charge
It's so consistent
doesn't matter what time frame we look at it on it's always the same with variations of cell basis holding
even that small cell base holds range beneath the range range beneath the range which is cell base is holding
range beneath the range uh here we go distinctive that's your technical break but that's your big break
there's nothing to say that price has to sell off immediately from here but here's your parabolic phase
and then price draws back up cool
In this instance, I can't see a clear break.
Because, you know, this is an individual pressure on itself.
It should have its own break.
What it does have is this last parabolic leg.
You can actually see the brakes and the gaps in it.
Where previously there wasn't any breaks or gaps.
It was actually really stable here, started selling off,
and then there would have a shot.
Anyway, let's have a look inside of it.
See if people break it down.
How do you even look on a chart like this?
What is this?
What I'm trying to show you is how there's a matter what time frame we're looking at price on.
The consistency is the same.
You see in cell bases holding bearishment flow, there's one large order here, 10 million.
As market orders are coming through, there's market order buying coming through, but it's just filling the sell orders, the sell limit orders.
When market order sales come through, the buy liquidity disappears, price pops out, that market order sell dries off, the sell liquidity is chasing price with it.
market order buyers are coming through the sell liquidity is holding price down the market the market order buyers aren't thick enough to push price up any market order sell or at the right time at least buy liquidity disappears price runs out that's light years in trading by the way for at least hFTs price runs out becomes super super thin leaving behind that void sell liquidity is back up there and any light buy volume pushes price right back up time and time and time and
time again. This mid-flow structure, price becoming parabolic towards the lows, is repeating
on every scale down to the minutest of scales. Why? As a result of how, in this instance,
at least, how orders are filled in the markets combined with specifically why the characteristics
of price runs occur. So why does price hold bases here, the large orders being filled the way they do?
why do these extensions dry off
if sellers are strong
why is price moving against the sellers
as we discussed
dealer behavior creating these
inefficiencies
creating a condition with his weakness
and lack of willingness to sell
and any buy volume
pushes price off
every single one of these
behaviors is occurring on every scale
as a result of these
the effect of the microstructure
so all
that's really the purpose behind it
and you know what if I had to argue
even on this shitty dollar price run
you have buy base hold
buy base push technical break
parabolic phase price gives in
it just happens time
and time again here you have your technical
break here that's your buy base
that's your break price continues
another break parabolic phase
you can just see nothing's happening here
price would have literally
just gone bam bam
within seconds
and then dries off comes right back in
this would have been classed as your break
so hardly any pullback missed no pullback deepest pullback to fancy equity and then break sideways pop it just keeps happening on all of the scales here's your distinctive break look run run run run base two highs distinctive break this one takes a bit of a while but here's your parabolic phase and it comes right back in we could even argue that this is even that was one price swing and then you have a larger price
on the way that now eventually gets full.
So if I show you this on the one minute,
it'll be much more clear with you.
This way, conflicting scale,
it can be a ballache
if you were to jump in live
and try to trade this now.
You have to build a collection of experiences
of what price might do
in each of these candle stages
that price is in.
So you can use your experiences
to set probabilistic expectations
of what should happen, shouldn't happen,
could happen, what each scenario looks like,
you take a Bayesian influence approach
which is basically
using incoming information
to form biases
or to basically
review your expectations
based off new information
rather than setting hard expectations
that price should do something
you never have hard opinions
you might hold them strongly
but no sorry you might have strong
conviction of the idea but loosely held
you're willing to let go of it
based on new information
and your ability to do that is based on experience
your brain internalizing the nature of trading
which is you're operating in an environment
that you never know what's going to happen next accurately
probabilities can change instantaneously
so you'll be really frequently exposed to being wrong
and these are the like small stuff as well
all of these things need a solution I provide a way to solve that
it's not a perfect solution.
A perfect solution would be God giving you a way to see the future.
That's the only perfect solution that would exist.
Perfect meaning you will consistently forever predict
what the market will do accurately next,
next accurately 100% of the time,
which is never going to happen.
So why, you know, how are we using price action
to predict future moves then?
Like we discussed, price behavior is consistent
because of the reasons we're discussing.
But then how are you taking advantage of price behaviours as they form?
We're just looking at historical charts right now.
Tell me what the next candle is going to do.
Tell me what these, you don't know, right?
Yeah.
Until you've built a collection of experiences
regarding all the different variations of price swings.
We've broken down price swing into different stages,
like mid-flow, sideways, parabolic phase, etc., etc.
You've internalized the characteristics of each of these stages.
just so you can spot them initially.
And you're still not there yet to now start tracking prices.
When you start tracking prices,
at each stage, a number of outcomes can happen.
And you need to experience each of those outcomes time and time again
until you have that robust collection of experiences
where you can now accurately tell me
what's most likely to happen,
what that will look like,
how you can take advantage of that,
what should not happen,
or what is possible, but what is less likely to happen,
what that would look like,
how you would be able to tell when that is happening
in every single phase or stage,
whether it's midflow, sideways,
break of midflow, pop,
taking entry, managing trade, etc., etc.
Every single part of the price swing
you should have experienced so much
and all the various outcomes,
so you can, your ability to assess what price should do is quite accurate.
And then from there, you take an approach of identifying what's favourable,
identifying the most favourable patterns and combinations of features
which consistently lead to the behaviours you want to exploit,
that you've seen work over and over again.
And you essentially are identifying what might happen based of the characteristics,
taking the trade and continuing to identify if the price is reflecting the characteristics of a winning trade.
So what I'm talking about here is pre-trade context, to trade entry, to post-trade management, every single step of the way.
If you're there to track it, you have the ability to assess probabilities in a lifetime.
You know what winners and losers look like.
You know the characteristics, the visual specific characteristics of each stage in.
price. You have a plan to assess the risks what's possible. You have the experiences and the
intuition to be accurate with what price should do. Then you have a possible solution in not
needing to know the future, but still being able to trade price. Until you have those
solutions and experiences, it will be difficult. And this is the primary reason people say
they have psychological issues in trading or psychology sort of issues of trade they don't have the
necessary intuition they don't have the necessary process that's appropriate for the market they try to
make hard predictions they hold on to their ideas too strongly they don't realize probably probably
probably is a dynamic they don't realize the small nuances in price which are telling them that
the trade is less likely to work none of these information is relevant to them or present to them
so they have only one thing to blame and it's basically the probability sorry they're the
psychology, right?
There'll be one pattern they rely on, basically.
It typically is one pattern.
It's like a market structure break or a Cozumodo, this type of pattern.
You can call that this like FTR super bullshit as well.
That's a madness like this.
Now, this pattern spotted on the right time frame,
that would be a trigger for them to trade.
Yeah.
But I could show you an enverbalt.
where almost majority of these pounds will lose of the types of levels price hits of the characteristics present here which increases the likelihood of price hitting your stop whereas they will just see the pattern and try to use that right so the time the environment comes where this pattern is going to likely fail over and over again they have no technological they have no framework to assess that environment so it's always a case of something that
times this pattern works sometimes it doesn't the times it's not working either they have super strict
discipline and they don't go mad so they continue to manage their risk well and they just wait their
time until the good time comes along which is fine but i'm talking about optimizing yourself to
identify the correct environment where you can batter the market and then also identify environments
where it's less conducive to trade as actively yeah like you said these patterns they're just
they're just going off like simple and you said it it's not mark it's just not simple like that
it's not appropriate you can't have a simple visual pattern applied holistically
throughout all types of environments and expect it to work yeah very true
when that stops working they have a bitch fit basically when the level of volatility changes
and price you know so they're used to i don't know there's a few variations yeah but they're
used to price doing this what about the day he price does this they're long here they're
exposed a huge drawdown what about them what about the day price does this oh here's your
break up mid-flow he's just taking their stops again hasn't it yeah exactly exactly but for them
never realizing that the trading in the most where there's random probably you know it's like
6040 70 30 50 50 they're not like there's not huge edge of trading that area
you have to have real small risk over time
and a high high number of these examples
so you can try to benefit of it
but yeah so these patterns
they don't know when they're going to work
or when they're not they have no capacity to recognize that
you will
what I'm saying is you want to be much more intimately
connected with price have the necessary
intuition be able to
before you even have that you need a visual framework
to be able to assess price at least
recognize what price is doing
if it's in mid-flow
when it's at the parabolic phase
see these price swings in detail
see the less obvious
from the obvious
all of those things combined
with your experiences
it all results in a skilled interface
when you're interacting with the market
a complete interface
that has solutions for
not knowing the future
but still trying to take trade
you know identifying where there's edge
identifying where there's the most skewed
for release seeing those things
work over and over again
and so it's validated for you.
We'll have a discussion on internalizing
within the following session,
but it's a bit of a primer at least
on the level of work
that's required
for you to internalize all of this.
I don't know who you've seen on RM, AD,
if you've seen anybody else,
Joshua, every single one of them does the work.
Every single one of them
would have been thinking of what you're thinking
now, this guy's making it sound
like it's rocket science and this is that.
it is basically for the normal person
who doesn't like doing work,
the equivalent of rocket science basically impossible for them.
For the normal person who wants to keep things simple,
trading is impossible for them.
And like I've said previously,
your trading plan and strategy can be simple.
I'll explain my strategy to you.
I'll write down in two words.
Fading weakness.
That's all my strategy is.
And if you wanted to,
you know, if you wanted to like be a,
bit more thorough about it is trading out core areas of liquidity at the parabolic phase so good
areas of liquidity at the parabolic phase i can write on a napkin but actually understanding what's
going on the two very very very very very separate worlds apart things my trading plans exploit in the
behavior here we're understanding you know what the behaviors are i'm not telling you that you need to be
accurately predicting that price is embellished midflow,
what type of midflow is going to be,
and then trading it every single second of it,
it's never going to happen.
Nobody does that.
It's more to do with being aware of what price is doing now,
what the implications of what price is doing right now is,
what the possibilities are,
how that affects the types of levels you can use,
the types of trading that can take place,
if any,
and being able to set probabilistic expectations
for what needs to have,
for your trade entries to work or for your trade ideas to work out so if I'm
trying to fade a bullish midflow it makes sense to wait for the break the parabolic
phase and then take my entry I know that the buy liquidity has weak and know the
buy liquidity in this price runs super super thin what I need is a decent level any
volume will quite easily cause price to run at least past that washed area
sometimes fully down to the core yeah we're using prices to
to assess where there's the most favorable conditions to trade based on comparing price against
the generic principles, the governing principles that we compare price against the reference points,
to the prism we view price through, and then simultaneously through validation. Through your
experiences, you validate that these prices do occur, they do consistently repeat, that you can
take advantage of them, and that's where your skill comes in, that's where the work comes in,
you need to have a proper structured planning
engage in the market there,
etc, etc.
Is that literally the only thing
you personally do now?
Yeah, what do you mean?
Like your trading plan
mid-flow?
Yeah, I don't.
Bro, I'm a very, very simple trader.
First touch of levels,
extensions and efficiencies only.
Yeah, otherwise, I mean, you know the whole,
you know it's all,
so you could be training at literally
any given time, really,
if you wanted to.
the way I see it yeah I can have a high high level of so let's have a look at a price here we broke midflow yeah
sell basis of hold I think we broke it multiple actually we broke it multiple times we had this
huge sell off relatively big that's 70 pips price broke midflow once twice three times but never
once did they go into the parabolic phase by the way and we'll define later how
on that great levels and then here we go into the distinctively parabolic phase right so we had the
weakness in this move quite early on we went to this parabolic phase finally and let's just you know
I want to trade at the point of exhaustion I might have got in there had to cut my trade took another
trade there cool after this I could be really really certain that price will break out and
continue higher but I still won't buy it because
even though I might be right, the probabilities of price continuing, like I said,
could be as good as 70-30 here.
Yeah.
But on a 70-30 scenario, you're still going to lose 10, 20 times in a row over a huge sample.
So if I only took this type of trade, I would still have times where I lose 10, 20, 30 times in a row.
But taking the entry at the point of exhaustion, I don't.
I don't lose 20, 30 times in a row.
I'd survive it if I did.
I lose five times in a row at times.
I cut off at three
so I'll walk away at three
come back I might lose two more
but I always walk away at three
but here
there's much more favourably skewed
probabilities
so that's all I want to take advantage of
I'm not trying to predict
where the market's going
I'm not trying to be God
I don't try and make
a thousand-pip price predictions
unless I'm feeling just like a bit
you know if I'm showing my ball to someone
and yeah I'll say that I expect price
to go there doesn't mean I would
You know, if I say cable's going to 150, it doesn't mean I'm longer in it.
Yeah, and it doesn't mean it will go there straight away either.
I'll probably short it more than I'll longer on the way to 150, which is a bit weird.
But it depends on how it gets to him, by the way.
And I never act on longer term price predictions.
The next one minute matters more to me than the next 30 minutes.
The next 30 minutes matter more than me than the next day.
The next candle, one second, one time.
tick candle
might as more than me
than the one minute
because I'm
always in taking on
I'm basically I'm always
aware of what price
are doing where it is
against the price swing framework
I know of how the lower
time frame fractal swings
fit in with a high time frame
swings I'm aware of all these things
which will come up with principles for
and I know at each individual
stage what probabilistically
is likely
here in essence
there is no
thin, thin
inefficiency
yeah?
So there is no
absolutely skewed probabilities
prices just tilted
to the upside
I would expect
this low to hold
but because there's
no skewed probabilities
at this point in time
and any number of things
can happen
will likely take this low out
will likely extend
passed into one of these
deeper bases
before any move higher
but as of right now
the probabilities are so balanced
that I won't have
a stronger opinion
of what price might do
however I might look ahead
and look for possible trace
So if price breaks, midflow, it extends inefficiently into, let's say, a fractal.
There might be a response there.
I'm looking ahead based on the current price swing, the current location and price,
based on my experiences on validation, I'm able to set relatively accurate.
Price comes down, a response.
In this move down, we had cell base hole, sell base hole, sell base hole, first break, pop,
into this call
you got a response
that would have been
three pips
15 pips
14 pips
5R
but within that instance
it could have easily
rose higher
it just wasn't conducive
for me to try and
take a trade here
because there wasn't skewed probabilities
it was relatively balanced
it could have risen
it could have sold off
I looked for a condition
where the probabilities
were skewed
here
are you following me
I was able to forecast ahead of time
very, very close to price, not 10 years ahead,
but that's my experience of price swings coming into play
and the consistency, why are these price swings consistent?
You have to ask this question because of the microstructure,
because of the way orders are filled,
all of the combination of things we've discussed
is creating these conditions consistently.
Just the same way, the large order here was being filled
it was drained to sell liquidity the inventory
which is at the stock go to a shop to have an inventory of products
the inventory of liquidity in this move
was grabbed so much so early on it drained it
it wasn't an intensively aggressive move
intensely aggressive move sorry it drained it
and then we finally
we basically went into another price run here
parabolic phase sideways pop into decent by liquidity
and that's where the trade would have been
yeah so yeah
hopefully I'm giving you a bit of insight into
how I don't need to know the future all the time
I can have
I can have multiple outcomes that are possible
and still not need to ready care
until price comes into that area where
the probability is suddenly skewed and I capture it
I pounce on it I just needed to have
anticipated it quite accurately
because what you don't want to do is
that condition come you see it too late you buy it here
and you're not buying in
at a thing
at a point in liquidity anymore.
The skill,
its experience,
is having the framework,
the language to describe price
in the first way,
your body has parts.
You don't call your fucking leg
your nose, bro.
Your leg does a job.
Your nose does a job.
You differentiate between the two.
A price swing has different stages
which reflect different things.
They have different characteristics.
And this is what we're essentially breaking down.
That is the how, right?
We're looking at how price, sorry, what we're talking about?
That is the what, you know, what are the characteristics of price behavior?
We've already, in giving you a primer, which remains a theme for how price behaves.
The thin inefficiencies, how the orders are filled, et cetera, et cetera.
That's what we're looking at.
We're combining the two.
This forms your foundation understanding.
Then on top of that, you build your experiences.
validate things you build a belief in the concept based on experience then you build skill and eventually
you come up with a process but it all starts with understanding and then obviously your belief in it
through validation yeah so this is a more of a structured well more thought out more appropriate way
to learn in a complex problem type environment in my opinion if if i'll be quite frank with you
it is overwhelming because I share like different types of information all the time
I'm crossing over with different things this is the easy part not not for you to
remember it necessarily but for you to like just deal with the information I'm not
expecting you to remember everything but why I do expect if you just deal with it yeah
because when you start to interact your price I'm telling you trade this 15 20
times and learn from it it's going to directly challenge your ego because
which everyone has.
You probably have a less ego than everyone else
because you read the miles and whatnot
I probably helped out in that respect.
It's a good thing that you have less of ego.
But when I'm telling you,
in Tractor Price,
that's where it's going to be the most difficult.
Oh yeah, I was just about to ask that.
Yeah, what's the most difficult bit there?
It's, I know it's overwhelming
the amount of information,
but everybody feels like that this way.
It's just critical if you understand where we're at.